Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1. Tlingit and English recordings, ca. 1950-1997 Bulk: 1970-1990
  - Jack David, 1950s, Tape 158.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR143)
    Speaker's English name: Jack David. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tsagwált. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Peace ceremony, peace songs, Lukaax.ádi trade songs. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Jim Marks, 1950s, Tape 159.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR144)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kuháanx'; Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Jim Marks songs. Kaagwaantaan songs, Shangukeidí songs. Jenny Klanott singing?. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label as well as "all are transcribed in Tlingit and translated 3/21/1983."
  - Jack David, 1950s, Tape 160.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR145)
    Speaker's English name: Jack David. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tsagwált. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Peace songs. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Andrew Gamble, 1950s, Tape 161.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR146)
    Speaker's English name: Andrew Gamble. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Small exerpts of multiple stories. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Unidentified, 1950s, Tape 162.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR147)
    Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Songs. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Jessy Kasko, 1950s, Tape 163.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR148)
    Speaker's English name: Jessy Kasko. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Aansanétk. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi. Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: History/geneology. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Esther Johnson, 1950s, Tape 164.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR149)
    Speaker's English name: Esther Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xeitl (Thunderbird). Speaker's Clan: Shangukeidí (Dry Bay area?). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Songs. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Jim Marks, 1950s, Tape 165.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR150)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kuháanx'; Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Stories. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Jessy Kasko, 1950s, Tape 166.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR151)
    Speaker's English name: Jessy Kasko. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Aansanétk. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi. Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Songs. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Henry Denny, 1950s, Tape 167.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR152)
    Speaker's English name: Henry Denny. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: unknown. Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Henry Denny. Description of contents: History, moieties, geneology.
  - Potlatch, multiple speakers, 1970s, Tape 168.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR153)
    Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description: Lukaax.ádi cry songs. A potlatch for Alfred Andrews hosted by James Klanott, Jenny Marks, Emma Marks, Horace Marks.
  - Potlatch, multiple speakers, 1970s, Tape 168.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR154)
  - Jenny Marks, August 6, 1972, Tape 169.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR155)
    Speaker's English name: Jenny Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Xus.een. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal);Taalkú (Devils Thumb Mtn). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Charms.
  - David Williams, August 11, 1972, Tape 170.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR156)
    Speaker's English name: David Williams. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaashdei yawdakaa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear), Cheech (Porpoise). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: unknown.
  - Betty Davis, Mary Johnson, Jenny Marks, Louise Williams, October, 1971, Tape 171.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR157)
    Speaker's English name: multiple. Speaker's Tlingit Name: multiple. Speaker's Moiety: multiple. Speaker's Crest: multiple. Speaker's Clan: multiple. Father's Clan: multiple. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Joking and fun making. Recording is poor.
  - Emma Marks; Willie Marks, February 15, 1973, Tape 172.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR158)
    Speaker's English name: Emma Marks; Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Seigeigéi; Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven); Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye); Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Dry Bay); Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Shangukeidí; Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Stories.
  - J.B. Fawcett, May 14, 1971, Tape 173.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR159)
    Speaker's English name: J.B. Fawcett. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tseexwáa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Toos' (Shark). Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Stories about the mines and other topics.
  - J.B. Fawcett; Ventura Sameniego, May 14, 1971, Tape 174.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR160)
    Speaker's English name: J.B. Fawcett. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tseexwáa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Toos' (Shark). Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Continuing stories and some songs.
  - J.B. Fawcett, August 23, 1973, Tape 175.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR161)
    Speaker's English name: J.B. Fawcett. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tseexwáa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Toos' (Shark). Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan (Hoonah). Father's Clan: T'akdeintaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Mt. Edgecumbe Hospital, Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Advice for Nora; stories.
  - Mrs. J.C. Johnson, April, 1971, Tape 176.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR162)
    Speaker's English name: Mrs. J.C. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaaxwaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Cheech (Porpoise). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Telling of stories and songs: the story of Glacier Bay, Gusuwaayei gunaanaa song, spiritual songs, (shaman songs), cry song, Lukaax.ádi and Chookaneidí songs.
  - Frank Williams, January 15, 1976, Tape 177.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR163)
    Speaker's English name: Frank Williams. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Koodénahaa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Gaanax.ádi (Ketchikan). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: English/Tlingit. Location recorded: Anchorage, Alaska. Recorded by: Jeff Leer. Description of contents: Jeff Leer interviews Frank Williams in both English and Tlingit.
  - Burt Dennis, June 29, 1970, Tape 178.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR164)
    Speaker's English name: Burt Dennis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Aankadaxtseen. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Devil's Thumb Mt). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description: Bert tells how he was being enticed (tricked) by Kooshdaa, and of a Chilkoot village that was totally wiped out by an avalanche, and all of his family Lukaax.ádi died. He tells about Talkú near Devil's Thumb Mt near Wrangell. Kooshdaa Hit Shaa Hit.
  - Burt and Marion Dennis, June 23, 1973, Tape 179.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR165)
    Speaker's English name: Burt and Marion Dennis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Aankadaxtseen. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Devil's Thumb Mt). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: English/Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description: Anniversary party; Speech, song, good times for Bert and Marion Dennis.
  - Burt and Marion Dennis, June 23, 1973, Tape 180.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR166)
    Speaker's English name: Burt and Marion Dennis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Aankadaxtseen. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Devil's Thumb Mt). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: English/Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description: Anniversary party, private singing group; Continuing celebrating. Kaagwaantaan singing and dancing.
  - Marion Dennis and Jenny Marks, June, 1973, Tape 181.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR167)
    Speaker's English name: Marion Dennis and Jenny Marks. Language: English/Tlingit. Location recorded: Haines, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description: Anniversary party, private singing group; Tlingit Salvation Army songs.
  - Jim Fox, August 23, 1972, Tape 182.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR168)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Fox. Speaker's Tlingit Name: We.há; Aan yaa laháash. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Gaanax.ádi (Taku). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: English. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Mrs. (Carol Beery) Davis. Description: Mrs. Davis (and husband) ask Jim Fox about history, his life, and family. (Mr. and Mrs. Davis were the first writers in Juneau, interviewing Tlingit people).
  - Jim Fox, June 27, 1973, Tape 183.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR169)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Fox. Speaker's Tlingit Name: We.há; Aan yaa laháash. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Gaanax.ádi (Taku). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: English/Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Mrs. (Carol Beery) Davis. Description: Mrs. Davis (and husband) ask Jim Fox about history, his life, and family.
  - Unidentified group, November 5, 1977, Tape 184.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR170)
    Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: "Presumably Part of Carol Beery Davis collection." Description of contents: Potlatch. Singing from Hoonah group. Potlatch for Yéil, Ch'áak' are giving comfort.
  - Willie Marks, 1980s, Tape 185.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR171)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Raven and the Whale story.
  - Willie Marks, 1970s, Tape 186.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR172)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Anchorage, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Stories and song. Weather, sneezing, and fun with cayenne pepper are some of the topics, as well as Shamanism.
  - Susie James, May 31, 1973, Tape 187.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR173)
    Speaker's English name: Susie James. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kaaxsgeiy. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Cheech (Porpoise). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: T'akdeintaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Songs. Susie singing lullabies and stories. Susie talks about peacemaking.
  - Mrs. Peter Johnny, August 12, 1972, Tape 188.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR174)
    Speaker's English name: Mrs. Peter Johnny. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: English/Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Interview. She tells of life and being a widow, about Kooshdaa sightings, interior trading, and Glacier Bay, when the glacier was coming down.
  - Andy Hope's Grandmother, November 30, 1972, Tape 189.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR175)
    Speaker's English name: Andy Hope. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: S'iknax.ádi (Taku Harbor). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: English/Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: A day in the life of Andy Hope and his grandmother whose name and clan are unknown.
  - J.B. Fawcett; Walter (Babe) Williams, undated, Tape 190.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR176)
    Speaker's English name: J.B. Fawcett; Walter (Babe) Williams. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tseexwáa; Keidlak'i Éesh. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle); Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Toos' (Shark); Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan (Hoonah); Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: T'akdeintaan yádi; unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Walter Williams and J.B. Fawcett conversation about the people that came down the river after the flood.
  - Willie Marks, March 16, 1973, Tape 191.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR177)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: ANB Memorial. David Williams memorial hosted by Willie Marks.
  - Willie Marks, March 16, 1973, Tape 192.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR178)
    Speaker's English name: Willie Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Keet Yaanaayí. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tlingit hymns. Russian Orthodox songs, Lord's Prayer. Amy Marvin, Nora Marks Dauenhauer, Richard Dauenhauer, Mrs. Pratt.
  - Hoonah Ladies, October 8, 1978, Tape 193.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR179)
    Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: ANB Memorial. David Williams memorial hosted by Willie Marks.
  - Austin Hammond, May, 1981, Tape 194.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR180)
    Speaker's English name: Austin Hammond. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Daanawáak. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Haines). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Chilkoot Lake, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Prayer for land at Chilkoot Lake.
  - Jenny Marks; Emma Marks, August 18, 1972, Tape 195.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR181)
    Speaker's English name: Jenny Marks; Emma Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Xus.een; Seigeigéi. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven); Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye); Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Talkú (Devils Thumb Mtn); Lukaax.ádi (Dry Bay). Father's Clan: unknown; unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Lullabies; Sitting with Jenny Marks. Emma giving her opinion occasionally.
  - Jack David, undated, Tape 283.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR182)
    Speaker's English name: Jack David; Al Andrews. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tsagwált; unknown. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven); Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye); Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Haines); Lukaax.ádi (Haines). Father's Clan: unknown; unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Songs.
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 1 and 2, August, 1980, Tape 284.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR183)
    Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Technical operations, Audio track for Haa Shaagóon.
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 3 and 4, August, 1980, Tape 285.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR184)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 5 and 6, August, 1980, Tape 286.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR185)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 7 and 8, August, 1980, Tape 287.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR186)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 9 and 10, August, 1980, Tape 288.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR187)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 11 and 12, August, 1980, Tape 289.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR188)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 13 and 14, August, 1980, Tape 290.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR189)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 15 and 16, August, 1980, Tape 291.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR190)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 17 and 18, August, 1980, Tape 292.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR191)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 19 and 20, August, 1980, Tape 293.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR192)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 21 and 22, August, 1980, Tape 294.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR193)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 23 and 25, August, 1980, Tape 295.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR194)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 42 and 43, August, 1980, Tape 296.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR195)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 44 and 45, August, 1980, Tape 297.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR196)
  - Chilkoot Peace Series, tape 46 and 47, August, 1980, Tape 298.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR197)
  - A.P. Johnson, undated, Tape 299.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR198)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: unknown. Description of contents: Tlingit (Kiks.adi) lifestyle. A.P. explains how to dry fish, what fish to use, and how to get them. He also tells of materials to use in the proccess of drying fish.
  - A.P. Johnson "dog salmon story - askw T'atseen", undated, Tape 300.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR199)
    Speaker's English name: A.P. Johnson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Ixt'ik' Eesh. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Xíxch' (Frog). Speaker's Clan: Kiks.ádi (Sitka). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: unknown. Description of contents: copy of tape 299. Poor recording. Raven and The Sea Urchin.
  - Origin of K'eik'w by Bill Davis; Robert Zuboff, June 20, 1974, Tape 301.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR200)
    Speaker's English name: William Davis; Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: unknown; Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: unknown; Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown; S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: unknown; Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: unknown; Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: unknown. Description of contents: Story of K'eik'w.
  - William Davis and Louis Kitkoon T-H language workshops, June, 1974, Tape 302.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR201)
    Speaker's English name: William Davis; Louis Kitkoon. Language: English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: unknown. Description of contents: Poor recording. Telling of Tlingit people, how they divide themselves. Speaker discusses possible styles for learning/teaching Tlingit culture.
  - William Davis and Louis Kitkoon workshops, June, 1974, Tape 303.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR202)
    Speaker's English name: William Davis; Louis Kitkoon. Language: Tlingit/English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: unknown. Description of contents: Poor recording. Bill Davis: Theory of origin of Raven-Eagle workshop, 6/17 (Tlingit); Louis Kitkoon "Raven and Whale" workshop, 6/17 (Haida/English translation).
  - Sitka Tradition Bearers' Conference, April 12, 1978, Tape 304.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR203)